Suppose you specify two tables in a query without
specifying a join. In that case, you will have
a cartesian product in which every record in one
table is related to every record in another. That
is usually done by accident, but, as we see with
this query, we are trying to display an inventory
sheet of every product in every location. Notice,
that with these two tables, Product and Location,
no specific join is specified, which indicates
a cartesian product. When I run this query,
every product is in every
location and one can print
this out and start taking inventory of
the products that are in each location.
If we want to, for the purpose of clarifying
the use of a query such as this query, we can
indicate that this query is a CROSS JOIN, which
is a cartesian product. I will change the comma
to the words CROSS JOIN and execute this query
again. The results are the same, so whether
one uses a comma or a CROSS JOIN clause, the
end result will still be a Cartesian product.